Guide to the Morse Hardware Company records 1891-1999
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
Morse Hardware Company records
1891-1999
Center for Pacific Northwest Studies Goltz-Murray Building 808 25th St Bellingham, WA 98225-9123 Phone: 360 650 7534 Email: cpnws@wwu.edu
XOE_CPNWS0020morsehardware
Morse Hardware Company
87 Linear Ft. 24 Boxes 271 Volumes
The Morse Hardware Company records reflect the activities of this multi-generational Bellingham, Washington based company from 1891 to 1999. Also included in the collection are Morse family materials which document the history of the Morse Hardware Company and the history of the local community which underscore the important role that this family-owned business served in the local community and the regional economy.
The Morse Hardware Company is one of the oldest mercantile businesses in the Northwest region and is also one of the oldest, continually operating family owned businesses in the area. The company was founded by Robert I. Morse, who sold his property in San Francisco and used the proceeds to purchase $3000 worth of hardware, paints, glass and other supplies and sailed for Bellingham Bay in 1884, determined to find a role in the booming economy of the Pacific Northwest.
Morse located his store near the waterfront at 1039 Elk St. and established his personal residence on the second floor. Initially, the store operated solely as a retail operation, but the success of the Morse merchandizing slogan "Sell 'em Low, Send and Get More" generated a loyal and growing customer base. As the business expanded Morse entered the wholesale trade as a supplier to the burgeoning number of crossroad establishments that served the growing population in the region.
The expansion of the railroad in the 1890's facilitated the shipment of supplies and merchandise and promoted additional growth in the business. The advent of World War I generated a demand for lumber and hardware for ship-building. The company supplied this endeavor and used the proceeds to expand into the Alaska cannery business, eventually becoming the dominant supplier of hardware and other supplies to this industry.
Upon the death of Robert I. Morse in 1920, his eldest son, Cecil A. Morse, assumed the duties of the president and general manager of Morse Hardware. Cecil held the company together during the Great Depression and although most employees accepted wage and salary reductions, the company managed to avoid any layoffs. Cecil's presidency also oversaw expansion in sales and marketing with sales territories and staff growing farther afield. World War II spurred an expansion of the industrial supply division of Morse Hardware as the company furnished shipyards with the supplies necessary to sustain the war effort. The company also purchased several new buildings adjacent to the original store to house a growing inventory.
After fifty-seven years in the business, Cecil Morse died in 1958 and David C. Morse, the youngest son of the founder, became president. David continued to expand distribution markets by making new inroads in Alaska and Oregon. In 1960, the store closed its individual retail outlet and focused operations on wholesale distribution to retail stores and heavy industry. The primary customer base became lumber yards, retail outlets, and home centers in western Washington, northern Oregon and Alaska. Industrial supply sales were complimented by the movement of the Mobil Oil Company refinery and the Intalco Aluminum Corporation in Whatcom County. Georgia Pacific and the Atlantic Richfield Co. also became Morse customers. In 1963, the company became a member of PRO Hardware, Inc. PRO was a voluntary international organization of wholesalers with several distributors located in the United States. The organization assisted wholesalers in developing and distributing merchandizing, marketing and promotional programs. Morse hardware successfully implemented the program through 50 of its dealers throughout western Washington and Alaska.
In 1975, Bob Morse, grandson of the original founder assumed the presidency. The final decades of the 20th Century witnessed significant change in business focus. In 1994, Morse Hardware Co. announced that it would cease supplying wholesale hardware goods to retailer stores and lay off 25 workers. And, in November of 1998, the company announced that it would sell its industrial supply division with operations in Bellingham and Tacoma to Stellar Industrial and Construction Supply. Stellar leased the original Morse Hardware site in Bellingham and Morse operations in Tacoma changed its name to Stellar. Prior to the sale, the Morse industrial division distributed nearly 12,000 items, including hand and power tools, cutting tools and abrasives, and mill and construction supplies. The sale allowed the company to focus on its core business, Morse Steel Service, which continues in successful operation in Bellingham. The warehouse building is a large tilt up concrete structure with two 55 foot bays served by seven overhead five and ten ton bridge cranes. The operation requires specialized machinery including a 5/8 inch shear, acetylene and plasma computerized cutting equipment, automatic saws, rebar bending machine, and an iron monger to fulfill diverse customer requirements. The product base is carbon steel, cut to all shapes and sizes, and utilized by fabricators, building constructors, and heavy industry.
The original building on State Street, houses the offices of the steel business. Morse Steel service also operates a similar, but smaller steel warehouse in Wenatchee.
The Morse Hardware Company records consist of three specific series spanning the years 1891-1999. These series are: 1) The records of the Morse Hardware Company, 2) Morse Family Materials, and 3) Bellingham and Whatcom County Historical Materials. The first series, the company records, comprise the bulk of the collection. This series includes Board of Directors meeting minutes, stockholder minutes, extensive financial material including ledgers and account books, sales records, invoices, daybooks, cash books, shipping and freight records, taxes, leases and other property records which document growth and change in business activity. The records also include extensive material documenting employees and employee functions. Marketing, merchandise and customer relations played an increasingly important role as the company grew and flourished. A large section of the collection documents this activity and includes a number of sales catalogs generated by Morse Hardware and other companies. These catalogs were used by the Morse sales staff as they canvassed their respective territories. Finally, the Morse company records include subject files maintained in the main office which document the humor, general interests, and business philosophy of the Morse family. The final two series were created by members of Morse family and include pamphlets, maps, photographs and manuscript material, which document the history of Morse Hardware and the history of the local community and which underscore the important role that this family-owned business served in the local community and the regional economy.
The collection is organized in accordance with the following series and subseries arrangement:
Series I: Morse Hardware Company, 1885-1994
Subseries 1: Stockholders and Board of Directors Records, 1897-1935
Subseries 2: Correspondence, 1890-1901
Subseries 3: Financial Records, 1884-1979
Subseries 4: Employees and Employee Functions, 1893-1991
Subseries 5: Merchandise, Advertising and Customer Relations, 1892-1994
Subseries 6: Subject Files (as organized by the Morse Family), 1890-1994
Series II: Morse Family Materials, 1886-1999
Series III: Bellingham and Whatcom County History, 1887-1990
Collection is open to the public.
Arrangements were conducted via David C. Morse who formally donated the records on August 26, 1996.
In 1996, staff from the Center for Pacific Northwest Studies surveyed the records of Morse Hardware on the site of the original business in Bellingham. Materials deemed to have archival value were inventoried for future transfer to CPNWS.
Heller, Ramon, Sell 'em low--send and get more: a centennial history of Morse Hardware Company, R. Heller, 1984.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Morse, Cecil A.--Archives.; Morse, David C.--Archives.; Morse, Robert I. --Archives.
Morse
Morse Hardware Company; Morse Steel Service; Stellar Industrial and Construction Supply
Business enterprises --Washington (State)--Bellingham.; Sales promotion --Washington (State) -- Bellingham.; Retail trade -- Washington (State) -- Bellingham; Hardware stores--Washington (State)--Bellingham; Hardware industry--United States--History.
Bellingham--Washington (State)--History.
Washington (State); Oregon; Idaho; Alaska; Diaries; Maps; Business, Industry, and Labor
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Morse Hardware Company, 1884-1994; Series I
  - Stockholders and Board of Directors Records, 1897-1935; Sub-series 1
    - Microfilm
      - Minutes of meetings of the Board of Directors, 1897-1964 (Box 1)
      - Stockholders Minute Book, 1901-1935 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1890-1901; Sub-series 2
    - Letters Received (“General Correspondence”)
      - “General Correspondence”, November 1893 (Box-folder 2/1)
      - A-B, 1894 (Box-folder 2/2)
      - C, 1894 (Box-folder 2/3)
      - D-E, 1894 (Box-folder 2/4)
      - F-G, 1894 (Box-folder 2/5)
      - H-J, 1894 (Box-folder 2/6)
      - K-L, 1894 (Box-folder 2/7)
      - M, 1894 (Box-folder 2/8)
      - N-Q, 1894 (Box-folder 2/9)
      - R, 1894 (Box-folder 2/10)
      - S, January-February 1894 (Box-folder 2/10)
      - S, March-September 1894 (Box-folder 2/11)
      - T-Z, 1894 (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Letters Received (“Foreign Letters”)
      - "Foreign Letters", Undated; July-December 1891 (Box-folder 2/13)
      - "Foreign Letters", January 1892 (Box-folder 2/14)
      - "Foreign Letters", February 1892 (Box-folder 2/15)
      - "Foreign Letters", March 1892 (Box-folder 2/16)
      - "Foreign Letters", April 1892 (Box-folder 2/17)
      - "Foreign Letters", May 1892 (Box-folder 2/18)
      - "Foreign Letters", June 1892 (Box-folder 2/19)
      - "Foreign Letters", July 1-15, 1892 (Box-folder 2/20)
      - "Foreign Letters", July 16-31, 1892 (Box-folder 2/21)
      - "Foreign Letters", August 1892 (Box-folder 2/22)
      - "Foreign Letters", September 1892 (Box-folder 2/23)
      - "Foreign Letters", October 1892 (Box-folder 2/24)
      - "Foreign Letters", November 1892 (Box-folder 2/25)
      - "Foreign Letters", December 1892 (Box-folder 2/26)
      - "Foreign Letters", (Unspecified month) 1893; January 1893 (Box-folder 2/27)
      - "Foreign Letters", February 1893 (Box-folder 2/28)
      - "Foreign Letters", March 1893 (Box-folder 2/29)
      - "Foreign Letters", April 1893 (Box-folder 2/30)
      - "Foreign Letters", May 1893 (Box-folder 2/31)
      - "Foreign Letters", June 1893 (Box-folder 2/32)
      - "Foreign Letters", July 1-15, 1893 (Box-folder 2/33)
      - "Foreign Letters", July 16-31, 1893 (Box-folder 2/34)
      - "Foreign Letters", August 1893 (Box-folder 2/35)
      - "Foreign Letters", September 1893 (Box-folder 2/36)
      - "Foreign Letters", October 1893 (Box-folder 2/37)
      - "Foreign Letters", November 1893 (Box-folder 2/38)
      - "Foreign Letters", December 1893 (Box-folder 2/39)
    - Letters Received (“Local Correspondence”)
      - A-B, 1896 (Box-folder 2/40)
      - C, 1896 (Box-folder 2/41)
      - D-E, 1896 (Box-folder 2/42)
      - F-G, 1896 (Box-folder 2/43)
      - H, 1896 (Box-folder 2/44)
      - I-L, 1896 (Box-folder 2/45)
      - M-N, 1896 (Box-folder 2/46)
      - O-R, 1896 (Box-folder 2/47)
      - S, 1896 (Box-folder 2/48)
      - T-Z, 1896 (Box-folder 2/49)
    - Letters Received (“Shingle Correspondence”)
      - “Shingle Correspondence”, 1894 (Box-folder 2/50)
      - A-E, 1895 (Box-folder 2/51)
      - F-M, 1895 (Box-folder 2/52)
      - N-X, 1895 (Box-folder 2/53)
      - Y, January-February 1895 (Box-folder 2/54)
      - Y, March-April 1895 (Box-folder 2/55)
      - Y, May-June 1895 (Box-folder 2/56)
      - Y, July-September 1895 (Box-folder 2/57)
      - Y, October-December 1895 (Box-folder 2/58)
    - Letter Press Books
      - "collection letters", March 11, 1890 to December 26, 1893 (Volume 1)
      - Letter Press Book, January 8 to August 4, 1894 (Volume 2)
      - Letter Press Book, September 3, 1894 to June 11, 1895 (Volume 3)
      - Letter Press Book, 1895-1897 (Volume 4)
      - Letter Press Book, May 22, 1896 to December 29, 1897 (Volume 5)
      - Letter Press Book, January 20, 1897 to February 8, 1898 (Volume 6)
      - Letter Press Book, December 24, 1897 to May 21, 1898 (Volume 7)
      - Letter Press Book, May 26-November 1, 1898 (Volume 8)
      - Letter Press Book, August 28, 1899 to January 20, 1900 (Volume 9)
      - Letter Press Book, January 20-June 1, 1900 (Volume 10)
      - Letter Press Book, June 4-October 14, 1900 (Volume 11)
      - Letter Press Book, October 16, 1900 - March 21, 1901 (Volume 12)
  - Financial Records, 1884-1979; Sub-series 3
    - Country Ledgers
      - “Transfer Country Ledger” (expenses, assets and liabilities), 1903-1931 (Volume 13)
      - “Country Ledger” (A-Z), 1923-1931 (Volume 14)
      - “Country Ledger” (A-Z), 1931-1962 (Volume 15)
      - “Country Ledger” (A-Z), 1931-1962 (Volume 16)
      - “Country Ledger” (A-Z), 1931-1962 (Volume 17)
    - General Financial Ledgers
      - Ledgers (monthly finances)
        - General Financial Ledgers, May 1897 to April 1898 (Volume 18)
        - General Financial Ledgers, May 1898 to April 1899 (Volume 19)
        - General Financial Ledgers, May 1899 to April 1900 (Volume 20)
        - General Financial Ledgers, May 1900 to April 1901 (Volume 21)
        - General Financial Ledgers, May 1901 to April 1902 (Volume 22)
        - General Financial Ledgers, May 1902 to April 1903 (Volume 23)
      - Ledgers with entries organized by day:
        - Ledger, October 1, 1892 to April 30, 1894 (Volume 24)
        - Ledger, September 1889 (?) to December 1890 (Volume 25)
        - Ledger, October 16-November 30, 1899 (Volume 26)
        - Ledger, April 1, 1890 to January 28, 1891 (Volume 27)
        - Ledger, November 1, 1905 to May 31, 1906 (Volume 28)
        - Ledger, June 1, 1906 to April 30, 1907 (Volume 29)
        - Ledger, April 26, 1907 to February 29, 1908 (Volume 30)
        - Ledger, February - December 1908 (Volume 31)
        - Ledger, December 1 to 31, 1909 (Volume 32)
        - Ledger, January 1-December 31, 1912 (Volume 33)
        - Ledger, January 1-December 31, 1913 (Volume 34)
      - Ledgers (non-chronological entries organized by subject)
        - Ledger, 1887-1888 (Volume 35)
        - Ledger, 1889-1890 (Volume 36)
        - Ledger, 1891-1893 (Volume 37)
        - Ledger, 1893-1895 (Volume 38)
        - Ledger, 1896-1897 (Volume 39)
        - Ledger, 1896-1897 (Volume 40)
    - Other General Financial Ledgers
      - Financial Information ( Ledger pages torn from volume), 1957-1962 (Volume 41)
      - Gasoline Inventory, 1959-1962 (Volume 42)
      - Vouchers Payable, 1960-1962 (Volume 42)
      - “Federal retail dealer’s excise tax payable", 1957-1962 (Volume 42)
      - “City business tax payable", 1958-1961 (Volume 42)
      - “Accrued life insurance payable" (Ledger pages torn from volume), 1959-1962 (Volume 42)
      - "General Ledger", 1971 (Volume 43)
    - Invoices, organized chronologically
      - Invoices, April 2, 1884 to June 11, 1887 (Volume 44)
      - Invoices, December 31, 1887 to April 20, 1889 (Volume 45)
      - Invoices, March to September 1889 (Volume 46)
      - Invoices, 1889-1890 (Volume 47)
    - Invoices and Credit Memoranda
      - A-G, 1890 (Box-folder 3/1)
      - H-P, 1890 (Box-folder 3/2)
      - R-Z, 1890 (Box-folder 3/3)
      - A-C, 1891 (Box-folder 3/4)
      - D-E, 1891 (Box-folder 3/5)
      - F, 1891 (Box-folder 3/6)
      - G, January-June 1891 (Box-folder 3/7)
      - G, July-December 1891 (Box-folder 3/8)
      - H-L, 1891 (Box-folder 3/9)
      - M-R, 1891 (Box-folder 3/10)
      - S, January-March 1891 (Box-folder 3/11)
      - S, April-June 1891 (Box-folder 3/12)
      - S, July-September 1891 (Box-folder 3/13)
      - S, October 1891 (Box-folder 3/14)
      - S, November 1891 (Box-folder 3/15)
      - S, December 1891 (Box-folder 3/16)
      - T, 1891 (Box-folder 3/17)
      - W, January-June 1891 (Box-folder 3/17)
      - W, July-December 1891 (Box-folder 3/18)
      - A-C, 1892 (Box-folder 3/19)
      - D, 1892 (Box-folder 3/20)
      - E-G, 1892 (Box-folder 3/21)
      - H-M, 1892 (Box-folder 3/22)
      - N-R, 1892 (Box-folder 3/23)
      - S, January-July 1892 (Box-folder 3/24)
      - S, August 1892 (Box-folder 3/25)
      - S, September-October 1892 (Box-folder 3/26)
      - S, November-December 1892 (Box-folder 3/27)
      - T-Z, 1892 (Box-folder 3/28)
      - A-C, 1893 (Box-folder 4/1)
      - D-E, 1893 (Box-folder 4/2)
      - F-G, 1893 (Box-folder 4/3)
      - H, January-June 1893 (Box-folder 4/4)
      - H, July-December 1893 (Box-folder 4/5)
      - I-L, 1893 (Box-folder 4/6)
      - M, January-June 1893 (Box-folder 4/7)
      - M, July-December 1893 (Box-folder 4/8)
      - N-R, 1893 (Box-folder 4/9)
      - S, January-February 1893 (Box-folder 4/10)
      - S, March 1893 (Box-folder 4/11)
      - S, April 1893 (Box-folder 4/12)
      - S, May 1893 (Box-folder 4/13)
      - S, June 1893 (Box-folder 4/14)
      - S, July-August 1893 (Box-folder 4/15)
      - S, September 1893 (Box-folder 4/16)
      - S, October-December 1893 (Box-folder 4/17)
      - T, 1893 (Box-folder 4/18)
      - W, January-March 1893 (Box-folder 4/18)
      - W, April-December 1893 (Box-folder 4/19)
      - Z, 1893 (Box-folder 4/19)
      - A-C, 1894 (Box-folder 4/20)
      - D, 1894 (Box-folder 4/21)
      - E-F, 1894 (Box-folder 4/22)
      - G, 1894 (Box-folder 4/23)
      - H, 1894 (Box-folder 4/24)
      - J-L, 1894 (Box-folder 4/25)
      - M, January-February 1894 (Box-folder 4/26)
      - M, March-April 1894 (Box-folder 4/27)
      - M, May-July 1894 (Box-folder 4/28)
      - M, August-September 1894 (Box-folder 4/29)
      - M, October-December 1894 (Box-folder 4/30)
      - N-R, 1894 (Box-folder 4/31)
      - S, January-February 1894 (Box-folder 4/32)
      - S, March-April 1894 (Box-folder 4/33)
      - S, May-June 1894 (Box-folder 4/34)
      - S, July-August 1894 (Box-folder 4/35)
      - S, September 1894 (Box-folder 4/36)
      - S, October 1894 (Box-folder 4/37)
      - S, November-December 1894 (Box-folder 4/38)
      - T-Z, 1894 (Box-folder 4/39)
      - A-C, 1895 (Box-folder 5/1)
      - D-F, 1895 (Box-folder 5/2)
      - G, 1895 (Box-folder 5/3)
      - H, January-July 1895 (Box-folder 5/4)
      - H, August-December 1895 (Box-folder 5/5)
      - I-L, 1895 (Box-folder 5/6)
      - M, January-June 1895 (Box-folder 5/7)
      - M, July-December 1895 (Box-folder 5/8)
      - N-R, 1895 (Box-folder 5/9)
      - S, January-March 1895 (Box-folder 5/10)
      - S, April-May 1895 (Box-folder 5/11)
      - S, June 1895 (Box-folder 5/12)
      - S, July 1895 (Box-folder 5/13)
      - S, August 1895 (Box-folder 5/14)
      - S, September-October 1895 (Box-folder 5/15)
      - S, November-December 1895 (Box-folder 5/16)
      - T-Z, 1895 (Box-folder 5/17)
    - Sales Books (contain general financial information)
      - Sales Book Ledger, December 7, 1889 to January 31, 1890 (Volume 48)
      - Sales Book Ledger, February 20 to September 30, 1890 (Volume 49)
      - Sales Book Ledger, April 1 to June 11, 1890 (Volume 50)
      - Sales Book Ledger, June 16, 1890 to March 1891 (Volume 51)
      - Sales Book Ledger, September 1, 1890 to March 10, 1891 (Volume 52)
      - Sales Book Ledger, October 1, 1891 to May 1892 (Volume 53)
      - Sales Book Ledger, June 1 to December 31, 1892 (Volume 54)
      - Sales Book Ledger, January 3 to August 1893 (Volume 55)
      - Sales Book Ledger, August 1894 to May 1895 (Volume 56)
      - Sales Book Ledger, May 1 to November 22, 1895 (Volume 57)
      - Sales Book Ledger, November 1895 to July 1896 (Volume 58)
      - Sales Book Ledger, April 1, 1897 to April 1, 1898 (Volume 59)
      - Sales Book Ledger, May 20, 1897 to January 31, 1898 (Volume 60)
      - Sales Book Ledger, August 1 to March 31, 1897 (Volume 61)
      - Sales Book Ledger, June 1 to November 1898 (Volume 62)
      - Sales Book Ledger, September 1 to April 28 (years not specified, 1902-1903 ?) (Volume 63)
      - Blank “Sales Book” (Volume 64)
    - Accounting Sales Books
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1917-1931 (Volume 65)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1932 (Volume 66)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1933 (Volume 67)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1934 (Volume 68)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1935 (Volume 69)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1936 (Volume 70)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1937 (Volume 71)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1938 (Volume 72)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1939 (Volume 73)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1940 (Volume 74)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1941 (Volume 75)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1942 (Volume 76)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1943 (Volume 77)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1944 (Volume 78)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1945 (Volume 79)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1946 (Volume 80)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1947 (Volume 81)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1948 (Volume 82)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1949 (Volume 83)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1950 (Volume 84)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1951 (Volume 85)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1952 (Volume 86)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1953 (Volume 87)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1954 (Volume 88)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1955 (Volume 89)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1956 (Volume 90)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1957 (Volume 91)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1958 (Volume 92)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1959 (Volume 93)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1960 (Volume 94)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1961 (Volume 95)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1962 (Volume 96)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1963 (Volume 97)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1964 (Volume 98)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1965 (Volume 99)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1966 (Volume 100)
      - Accounting Sales Book, 1967 (Volume 101)
    - Cash Journals
      - Cash Journal, January 1890 to May 1894 (Volume 102)
      - Cash Journal, April 30, 1894 to December 31, 1895 (Volume 103)
      - Cash Journal, May 1, 1894 to July 6, 1895 (Volume 104)
      - Cash Journal, May 20, 1897 to August 31, 1898 (Volume 105)
      - Cash Journal, September 3, 1898 to January 31, 1900 (Volume 106)
      - Cash Journal, February 1, 1900 to January 1, 1901 (Volume 107)
      - Cash Journal, February 1, 1901 to August 30, 1902 (Volume 108)
      - Cash Journal, December 2, 1901 to August 30, 1902 (Volume 109)
      - Cash Journal, September 1, 1902 to April 30, 1903 (Volume 110)
      - Cash Journal, July 1, 1904 to March 31, 1905 (Volume 111)
      - Cash Journal, April 1 to October 1, 1905 (Volume 112)
      - Cash Journal (Organized by name), 1905-1906 (Volume 113)
      - Cash Journal, March 1 to December 31, 1908 (Volume 114)
      - Cash Journal, January 2 to November 30, 1909 (Volume 115)
      - Cash Journal, January 1 to December 31, 1910 (Volume 116)
      - Cash Journal, January 3 to December 31, 1911 (Volume 117)
      - Cash Journal, April 1, 1932 to April 30, 1935 (Volume 118)
      - Cash Journal, May 14, 1935 to April 30, 1937 (Volume 119)